# VANESSA KOSIYANON

#### FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

+1 661-600-6925



vkosiyan@gmail.com



vanessa-kosiyanon.com



linkedin.com/in/vkosiyan in



github.com/vkosiyan



## **EDUCATION**

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER **IMMERSIVE**

General Assembly, Los Angeles, CA

# BACHELOR OF ARTS, **PSYCHOLOGY**

University of California, San Diego

# SKILLS

React.js • Python • JavaScript HTML • CSS • Node.is Express • MongoDB • Git Django • Mongoose • Restful

# KEY SKILLS

Software Development Website Administration Project Management Writing & Editing Content Development Budgeting and Planning Client Support **Public Relations** 

#### AWARDS

# Be Awesome Award

JuJuBe / August 2019 & June 2018

#### Most Spirited

Polaris Management December 2017 & December 2016

#### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Software Engineer and swiss-army knife with training and experience in building websites and applications from the ground up. An award-winning employee with over five years of professional working experience and a background in Human Resources, Product Development, and E-Commerce. Professional strengths include creative problem-solving, project management, strong verbal and written communication, and an infectious positive attitude.

# EXPERIENCE

## GENERAL ASSEMBLY, LOS ANGELES, CA

Full-Time Software Engineer Immersive Fellow (October 2020 – January 2021) Completed a 12-week full-time intensive program with over 480 hours of project-based curriculum focused on programming, data structures, and modern frameworks with hands-on experience in peer programming, database development, CRUD operations, RESTful routing, OOP, and Git version control.

#### **Noted Projects**

- Bookish Developed a book search app utilizing the Google Books and NY Times Best Sellers List APIs to render search results and information on individual books. The app uses JWT for user sign up and log in, as well as AWS for user profile image uploads. Tech Used: React.js, Node.js, Mongoose, MongoDB, Express, RESTful API, Axios, JWT, Amazon S3, Semantic-UI-CSS, Semantic-UI-React, JavaScript, HTMLS, CSS3
- Goal Tracker Collaborated in a team of three to create a goal list app that utilizes full CRUD operations to allow users to create and manage their goals and resolutions. The app uses user sign up for security and allows the ability to make goals and lists private from other users.

Tech Used: Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Node.js, Mongoose, MongoDB, Express, Amazon S3, JavaScript, HTMLS, CSS3, Bootstrap

• You Should Try Media Recommender - Developed a TV show recommendation app that uses Google OAuth and full CRUD functionality to add TV shows and lists of TV shows to the database. Users can create lists of recommended shows (eg: Favorite Action Shows) and edit as they like. Users are also able to add show reviews or comments.

Tech Used: Mongoose, MongoDB, Express, JavaScript, OAuth 2.0, HTMLS, CSS3

• Minesweeper (Among Us) - Created a pure JavaScript implementation of the minesweeper game with fun graphics, animations, and sounds from the video game "Among Us".

Tech Used: Vanilla JavaScript, HTMLS, CSS3

# JUJUBE, IRVINE, CA

# Product Manager (August 2019 - August 2020)

- Managed the full life cycle of products from inception to product launch.
- Communicated and worked closely with offshore factories to ensure production met strict deadlines and milestones in the production cycle.
- Point of contact for licenses and brand partners (including Disney, Warner Bros, Blizzard, and Sanrio) for business and creative communication.

# Manager of eCommerce and Digital Marketing (Nov 2018 -Aug 2019)

- Lead website management including merchandizing and working closely with developers for the redesign of JuJuBe.com to ensure better user experience.
- Executed and managed all email marketing campaigns through Klaviyo.
- Managed external contractors and internal designers to ensure project deadlines were met on time and within budget.
- Compiled and analyzed monthly reports for all Ad spend and return to improve monthly numbers and sales.

Office Manager (May 2018 - Nov 2018)

# POLARIS MANAGEMENT (AN IQVIA COMPANY), NEW YORK, NY

Office Manager & HR Specialist (June 2016 - March 2018) Recruiting and Office Coordinator (April 2015 – June 2016)